It all begins with words
uttered by individuals,
repeated by others,
and became a philosophy and ideology.
[music]
But Germany's maniacal urge to impose
its will on others continues [music]
from generation to generation.
>> We must insist that the story be
complete full and the truth.
>> Our movement, the BDS movement, the
Palestine solidarity MOVEMENT IS FINALLY
STARTING TO REFRAME the conversation.
After a three-hour standoff, police
found both suspects dead in the store
along with three victims. Overnight,
thousands gathering to lay two of the
victims to rest. A community bound by
faith now praying for peace.
>> Words
was the basis for the murder of 6
million Jews of Europe.
The BDS movement that stands for
boycott, divestment, and sanctions. It's
very well funded and it's spreading
across college campuses in the US.
>> We've seen a dramatic uptick [music] uh
in anti-semitism. 100% increase on on
college campuses, 100% increase K
through 12.
>> We are going through a period of
turbulence in world history that is very
rare. It only happens every century or
so.
>> Why do they feel that way? just because
we're Jewish. I just felt it was unfair.
>> They're calling for the complete
destruction of Israel.
>> Another anti-semitic attack in New
[music] York. It's the latest in a
series of violent incidents targeting
the Jewish community.
>> The Jewish people have gone through many
holocausts.
>> The NYPD on Wednesday shared
surveillance video of another
anti-Semitic [music] attack in Brooklyn
last week, which shows a group of people
strike a 23-year-old hidetic man over
the head with a chair.
>> You can divide the world into two
groups. This [music] is a battle of the
decent against the indecent.
>> The notion that somehow um we've become
this this separate group of citizens
that [music] it's okay to heap scorn
upon us is so heinous and it's not
something that was ever thought [music]
to be what America is.
>> After 11 people were murdered at a
Pittsburgh synagogue,
>> the gunman killed one person and [music]
wounded three others inside a Southern
California synagogue on Saturday night.
The gunman took aim [music] at Rabbi
Yrael Goldstein.
>> We have anti-semitism in our
universities with college and university
[music] professors brainwashing our
children against the Jewish people.
Anti-semitism is not a Jewish problem.
It's everybody's problem.
>> Anti-semitism is on the rise in America.
The suspect using his arsenal of weapons
to try and kill as many Jews as he could
now faces a myriad of hate crime and
murder charges. We learned from history
that anti-semitism flourishes during
times of uncertainty, blaming a group uh
for problems
is attractive to achieving sometimes
political ends.
>> The BDS movement is growing and has
become a force on more and more college
campuses. It is aimed at only one
nation.
>> No other country, [music] just Israel.
>> All day, people slowly filtered into
Hebrew Cemetery to see if their family
headstones were vandalized. The result
of what police are calling a hate crime.
>> So far this year, 36 anti-semitic crimes
have been reported in the city. Compare
that to only 21 at the same time [music]
last year.
>> When you become anything without
realizing that it's [music] happening,
it's called brainwash. Well, was this
just harassment or was this harassment
because they weren't Jewish?
>> BDS is an attempt to economically
strangle one of the [music] 200
countries on earth. The only one is
Israel.
>> And every time we utter a word, a
sentence or a paragraph, we need to
think twice.
Will this result in hatred
or will it create harmony?
Yeah.
Heat.
[music]
>> [music]
>> The promise for tomorrow.
The promise for tomorrow.
Maybe
pain.
A life full of love. [music and singing]
A life full of love and the suffering.
The kind of life brings.
If I could speak every language
on earth or in heaven,
the words [singing] I speak would mean
nothing.
without
[music]
[singing] time.
>> [music]
[singing and music]
>> Yeah. Yeah. Without
>> [music]
>> I was born in 1929,
exactly halfway. way between [music] end
of World War I and beginning of World
War II in a fabulous place, [music] a
country called Czechoslovakia,
which was formed for the first time in
1918,
a country that tried to emulate much of
the best of America. And I'm born into a
Jewish family, middle class.
And so I lived in this beautiful house
with my parents, grandparents, loving
family, a small town of about 7,000
people. It was a modern town. There were
Jews and Catholics and Protestants and
Russian Orthodox living in the same
community side by side. There was no
area it could say Jews live in this
area, Catholics in this area. None
[music] of that. Totally integrated. And
I'm just a kid. I really don't know much
about what's going on in the world.
After all, in 1936,
I was 7 [music] years old.
In 1935,
I started school here in Hume and I
liked school and so life was beautiful,
right?
But at the same time things were
happening
other places.
There's a country called Germany.
They decided to build an army
and a navy and an air force airplanes
with bombs.
And one day they said to Czechoslovakia
that they want to take away one part,
wanted to become Germany. Czechoslovakia
didn't like that. But they didn't have
much of an army,
so they couldn't fight.
And so different people told them, "You
can take it.
You will see that if you continue this
and go north, you'll come to Poland. On
this street goes the German army. I
watched them from my window.
And my window faced this street.
If you go from Germany, you can go this
way into Poland, but you can also go
this way, this way.
So, thousands of people from the German
army
went through Hume
to Poland
and World War II began.
But soon things begin to change. One day
I'm carrying my friend's books
and she looks at me and she says, "I
don't want you to carry my books. In
fact, I don't want to talk to you
anymore." I say, "Why?" "Cuz you're a
Jew." And my father told me a not to be
friendly with a Jew. Socially, it's
unacceptable.
And B, you're evil.
In fact, you as a Jew are responsible
for every single things that goes wrong
in the world.
Thus begins the transformation
of society
on an individual basis. Things have
changed. I'm no longer the same person
as I was before. I haven't changed, but
the world is changing [music] around me.
And thus begins
the [snorts] slippery slope
of persecution of Jews, in particular
the persecution of Irving Roth.
I was an anti-semite. I hated Jews. I
hated America. The Jews were the reason
for all the evil in the world. I was the
person
who believed that killing Jews was the
right thing to do and a world without
Jews was a better place. So I grew up in
the UK in England in a place called
Nottingham, famous for Robin Hood. Um
but my grandparents, they came to the UK
from Pakistan. Very conventional
immigrant story. They came for better
economic opportunities, better
educational opportunities, etc., etc.
And as I think is very common with any
new immigrant community, they lived in a
neighborhood which was predominantly
Pakistani Muslim. And look, it was a
nice place to grow up. There are issues
in the Muslim community with extremism,
but when I grew up, it wasn't so much of
an issue.
But there was one topic that whenever it
came up, it would elicit a level of
hatred which was beyond irrational. And
that was the Jews. Israel, the Jews, it
was all seen as one in the same thing.
And the interesting thing about that was
this focus on Jew hatred. We didn't know
anybody Jewish. We had no interactions
with anybody Jewish. We had no Jewish
neighbors. We had never met anybody or
came across anyone Jewish. But there was
this hatred of Jews and the Jewish
people to the extent that my father
would frequently say that Hitler was a
great man and his one mistake was that
he didn't murder enough Jews. Growing up
in Britain, there was a disconnect. My
grandparents' parents had grown up or
been born in Pakistan
while I was born in Britain and felt not
exactly Pakistani. My first language was
English, theirs was Erdo, etc., [music]
etc. But also, there was an issue with
identity. Sadly, for many people,
because I wasn't white, I wasn't really
seen as British. And when I would go to
Pakistan, I wasn't seen as Pakistani.
And that was something that so many of
my peers, so many of my friends, and
people in my community and other British
Muslim communities beyond had this same
issue. into this void, into this
situation, more extremist voices emerged
and more extremist groups entered. They
came into communities and they reached
out directly to my demographic. They
used religion as a a door into their
their lives because growing up Muslim,
it's not something you do once a day. It
is your 24/7. But these groups had more
nefarious aims. They had a a political
agenda and they had [music] a more
extreme long-term goal. And one of the
worst and most dangerous things they did
was create this narrative that we were
victims. That living in the UK as a
Muslim, you're a victim of British
society. It's us versus them. It's a
it's a clash of civilizations
essentially. The dangerous thing with
that was that we weren't actually
victims. But once you believe you're a
victim and you're not, you one don't
have any way to address the roots of
your victimhood. And two,
you start to justify things that you
wouldn't normally be okay [music] with.
You wouldn't be okay with the killing of
civilians, but when you believe that
you're the greater victim and these
people are somehow linked to your
oppressor, you'll make excuses [music]
for it. This was the '9s, so you would
have flyers handed to you with really
shocking, grotesque, and heartbreaking
images of dead children, people with
limbs missing. Just really shocking. And
with those images would accompany a
caption such as, "This child was killed
by Israel because she was a Muslim," or,
"This this child was killed by the Jews
because she was a Palestinian." You had
no way to discern if those images were
factual, if they were real. But when you
see an image like that, you're instantly
shocked and horrified. So your reaction
to that is emotive. It's not, let me now
question the veracity of this image.
It's not, let me question, is this
really [music] a child who's killed in
this place. But what this does is it
creates a dehumanizing and desensitizing
effect.
I fear that we have lost an entire
generation
because we have um failed our children
in the universities [music] in high
schools. We as adults weren't there when
it mattered most. There is a focused
coordinated effort to demonize the
Jewish people specifically on many
campuses. The price of going being safe
as a Jewish student on college campus is
to divorce oneself completely to one's
connection with the state of Israel with
Jewish peoplehood and with Zionism.
>> We we have to touch people and we have
to undo indoctrination that western
children get from from kindergarten.
It's a very very real problem.
So unfortunately
you have some people who brainwash
children to hate. We see that in the
schools run [music] by kamas in Gaza. We
see that in the schools run by the
Palestinian Authority in the West Bank.
We see that unfortunately in many
classrooms across the greater Middle
East [music] where people are taught,
young people are taught to hate. It's
good to hate. You should hate the Jews.
They are evil.
And so by June of 1941,
Europe
is Nazi.
We hear rumors that Jews in the Soviet
Union are being shot. We don't believe
it. How could the possibly be? innocent
people, children,
women being murdered on mass
can possibly be.
But it continues.
By the time 1941 is over,
over half a million Jews in the Soviet
Union have been murdered,
buried in mass graves.
But the objective is the total
destruction of the Jewish population of
Europe.
And as they count the number of deaths,
they realize that in 6 months they
managed to kill a half a million people.
Since there is 11 million Jews living in
Europe, at this rate it would take 11
years to [music] get rid of all the
Jews.
Totally unacceptable.
And so when you have a problem in a
government, what you do is you convene a
conference. The task that was given the
group sitting there is how are we going
to
achieve our final solution
quicker and certainly cheaper.
And being there's so much brain power
there in an hour and a half,
they come up with a solution.
What we will do is we'll build death
camps. We'll bring Jews from all over
Europe to these death camps. The death
camp itself will have two basic
mechanisms. One is gas chambers and a
crematorium.
And this way the Jews will be murdered,
their bodies burned, and all that's
going to be left of the Jews of Europe
will be ashes.
And then they went to lunch.
In the 1930s, Jews 2% of the population.
What had happened to Germany in the
preceding [music] decades? Number one,
it lost the first world war. Number two,
it had to survive the penal punitive
conditions of the treaty of uh
Versailles. And number three, it
suffered hyperinflation.
Now anti-semitism had everything to do
with those three things and almost
nothing to do with Jews. But Hitler
understood that hate is a very powerful
political weapon. The Nazi leadership
needed the cooperation [music]
and acquiescence of large numbers of
people and they used propaganda. [music]
The Holocaust couldn't have taken place
without ordinary people uh playing a
role.
In 53 days,
437,000
Jews were taken from their home into
cattle cars
to Awitz.
I wind up in a cattle car.
100 people inside [music] a box.
The train begins to move.
One day, second day,
it's crowded.
Where are we going?
Finally, on the end of the third day,
our train is pulled into
some kind of enclosure. Seems like
it's night time. The doors are slid
open.
I look out there and I see a platform, a
gravel [music]
platform. Guards screaming and yelling,
"Harouse, get out quickly. Oh, take
nothing with you. It'll be all delivered
to you." I jump off the train and I look
around. In the distance, I see flames
coming out of chimneys.
And here I'm [music] 14 years old,
standing next to my grandfather,
looking around. What is this place?
This is where the decision was made. Who
shall live and who shall die? My
grandfather was Shimon Rosenwer.
My grandmother Rachel Rosenwer. My
brother Andrew or as we called them
Bandi.
My cousin Zultan.
My little
cousin Edith. She was about 10 years
old.
That was the immediate family inside
this cattle car. Of my transport of
about 4,000 people.
300 was separated from the whole group.
I among them my brother and some
cousins.
The rest of the group, 3,700 or
thereabouts,
were marching straight forward.
We did not know where they're going.
We're marched
through a gate to another part of the
camp. We're told to get undressed. That
clothing is taken away. We shaved top to
bottom.
We got a striped gray blue striped pants
and jacket and hat standing formation
for hours on end.
It's night time. It's the middle of the
night. We're tired. We're exhausted.
We're hungry and thirsty. And finally,
we're allowed to go into a building.
They're in the building.
There no beds there. I call them
shelves.
What they are is basically
deep shelves.
planks.
That's where we sleep. As we standing in
information, suddenly I look around and
I see that some people are bringing
little tables
like
school tables [snorts] with chairs on
either side. every call to sit down
on one side and on the other side stand
sits a man in a similar striped uniform
but he has something on the table itself
something which looks like a hypodermic
needle
and an inkwell
tells me to roll up my sleeve
and as I roll up my sleeves put my hand
down
he takes the hypoderminating needle and
starts poking my hand. And suddenly as I
look at it, there's a number on my arm.
I'm no longer a person with a name. I'm
now a number. I'm now the property of
the German government to do as they
please.
This death camp of Ashitz [snorts]
was
capable of taking 10 to 12,000 human
beings
and convert them to ashes in every
24-hour period.
And that night I had no grandfather or
grandmother, aunt or cousin
and I have [music] been tattooed.
I'm assigned to work. I wind up
eventually working with horses. Now here
I am 14 years old. I've never worked. I
lived in a city. But how do you take a
team of horses,
hook them to a plow,
drain the swamps of Awitz, and plow the
fields. That to me is a mystery.
But I learn very quickly because if you
don't learn, you don't last very long.
And one day I'm told to go to the field
and pick up straw in my wagon. And so I
have a guard who gets onto my wagon and
we're chucking along at a distance,
maybe a mile or so, maybe two. Uh there
is uh the crematorial and flames are
coming out of it and another one, four
of them. He says to me, "What are those
factories doing?"
Very funny.
He said, "What they do there? these
people are murdered and their bodies are
burned and ashes are then disposed. He
says, "You don't really believe that, do
you?"
I said, "Well, that's what goes on
there." And he says, "You don't believe
that, do you? I mean, why would we do
that?
We're fighting a war, two wars on two
fronts. We need manpower." So, I said,
"Ask your friends tonight."
Maybe a month goes by and I'm seeing him
standing above a bunch of prisoners
screaming and yelling at them. You dirty
Jews, you should be all shot and burned
because you're lazy.
He was transformed.
The environment,
the fact that the Jew was not a person
but vermin
got into his mind.
A decent person was converted,
transformed.
I can't be like him. I mustn't be like
him. I must not be subsumed
by the evil around me.
If I hate someone because he's too short
or too tall, if I hate someone because
he's a different color or religion, I'm
like him. I'm subsumed by the
environment, by the evil environment.
That's not me. I mustn't be.
There's something about hating Jews
which has an energy
uh that is difficult to explain and it
also has the ability to make itself
relevant to a new generation
and it's very dangerous. Something has
to be said about anti-mitism though.
It's not just about the Jews. There's
the old metaphor that anti-semitism is
like the like the canary in the coal
mine. that when someone says I'm against
the Jews, you have to ask a question,
what [music] else is this person about?
Because like the canary in the coal
mine, it might start with the Jews, but
it won't end with the Jews. That's for
sure. [music]
>> Uh first of all, anti-semitism
is a prejudice. And [music] think about
the etmology of the word prejudice.
Prejudge.
Don't confuse me with the facts. [music]
I've made up my mind. So, it's an
prejudice is always irrational because
you've made up your mind before you've
met the person. [music] It's not
disliking a Jew, but it's disliking a
person because they are a Jew. Well,
Hitler said that [music] propaganda
was a truly terrible weapon in the hands
of an expert. And the Nazis were quite
sophisticated and innovative [music] in
their use of propaganda. This is part of
how deeds become action [music] is the
constant messaging of dehumanization
of blaming and scapegoating and putting
people in a mindset where they would
stand back and let the state take care
of these problems that they had
identified.
The embracing of a more radical and
extremist ideology happened for me in
2000. I went to Pakistan to visit family
and for the first time I saw an actual
terrorist group, came face to face with
an actual terrorist group. What appealed
was I'd seen all of this graphic imagery
of reportedly or allegedly Muslims being
killed by the Jews or the West or
however it was portrayed. And now I saw
graphic imagery of a different sort. I
saw these bellose statements of
defeating the enemies of Islam,
destroying America, destroying India,
destroying Israel. And while that may
seem
strange or scary from a western
perspective, when for years you've
absorbed this narrative of being a
victim and only seeing what you see as
your people being oppressed, here was
somebody fighting back. I was at that
place where I was able to make that jump
that yes, they kill innocent civilians.
But when you look at what is happening
in the Muslim world, what Israel is
doing, what India is doing, what America
is doing, I can understand why they do
this. You've now crossed the first line
of what is okay and not okay where
you're you can understand why innocent
civilians are killed.
So when I went back to the UK, I started
looking more into Leha and other groups
like that and they follow a very extreme
interpretation of Islam.
But as I read these different
perspectives from different groups and
different organizations,
one thing really stood out to me,
the Jew hatred. Every single one of them
had this familiar theme of no matter
what it is, their main issue may be
fighting India and Kashmir. It may be,
you know, trying to destroy Israel. It
may be trying to get America out of
Saudi Arabia.
All of these groups tied everything back
to the Jews. That behind everything
there was a Jewish hand which was trying
to destroy Islam, destroy Muslims and
oppress Muslims. I saw my anti-semitism
as a positive. I saw my anti-semitism as
being pro- Palestinian.
My my anti-semitism as being pro- my
people. I get to college and very early
on, first few days, I go to an event and
we watch this video which again uses
this very graphic imagery with little
context, no narration ending with the
statement, what are you doing for your
brothers and sisters in Palestine?
But when I was at university, I became
very active in the anti-Israel movement.
And I call it the anti-Israel movement
cuz that's what it was. And I got to a
point where everything I was doing
wasn't enough. So for me, the the
rational conclusion of this was
violence, violence, terrorism. It makes
a statement and it focuses the world's
attention. And in my mind, the Jews were
so evil that this was just. So I started
thinking about and looking at ways I
could travel back to Pakistan and go to
a terrorist training camp and then do
whatever I had to do to really fight for
my cause.
Tens of millions of people are convinced
today
that this process in some form somewhat
repackaged need to be repeated and get
rid of the Jews again. The lies that
were perpetrated then have been
repackaged
in the 21st century form.
But the end result is the same. The
destruction of a people.
One morning we get up and ready to go to
work. We're at the gate.
We're not marching to work. We're
marching away from Awitz
on a death march.
You march or you die.
It's cold.
It's snowing.
We're marching.
I'm hungry.
I'm tired.
I'm bloody cold.
And I complain to my brother
and he looks at me. He said, "Trouble
with you is you're so physical.
Stop worrying about these physical
things.
Do something more esoteric.
I'm hungry. What do you want me to do?
To [snorts] say a prayer.
The hunger won't go away, but you'll
feel better.
I suppose I did. And so we're marching
for 3 days.
Finally, we put into trains, open cars
in the middle of the winter. Hours go by
and we're in a new place,
a concentration camp called Bhvalt.
I'm trying to hold on.
My brother is very helpful.
He talks to me and one day he's taken
away.
I didn't say goodbye to him.
I remember the day
because up to that point I always had
someone to lean on,
someone to speak to
would give me hope, would encourage me.
What am I to do alone?
I continue talking to him though he
wasn't there.
I would ask myself, what would he say?
He wasn't evil.
All the stories that people make up
throughout the world
about the Jew, my brother,
gentle,
kind,
sweet human.
All the lies.
All the lies today on the airwaves.
He committed no crime.
Yet
hundreds of thousands of people,
people who guarded this place
consider him to be vermin.
This gentle, sweet human.
[music]
[singing]
>> [music and singing]
>> is
[music]
[singing]
like
[music and singing]
God.
[singing]
[music]
>> [singing]
>> They [music] shall
fall.
[music and singing]
Their blood cries out to the sky.
I [music and singing] said,
"Why is our faith
ask how [music] long will you wait?
[music]
[singing]
So
[music]
I
n I love
[music]
So here I am 15 years old
slowly losing more and more weight. I'm
down to about 75 pounds or so.
I'm in a barracks with about 200 or so
kids,
15 year olds,
trying to survive,
hoping that the war is going to be over
soon and somehow by magic
I will survive. It's April of 1945 and
suddenly
beginning of April, they're death
marches again.
Now I know what the death march is. I
know I'm not going to survive because
I'm down to 75 miles. I can hardly drag
myself. Never in my march at a pace the
guard set. Lines are being formed.
Guards are assembling
and I know
I won't last more than a day or two.
[music]
Suddenly the siren goes off. There's an
air raid. American airplanes are
overhead. They're bombing the city of
Weimar
some 3 4 kilometers away
and the air raid lasts all day long
and the guards wait
and I survive another day.
By next morning, [music]
April 11th,
things aren't moving so fast. By 11:00,
we look around. There are no guards.
Not inside the camp, nor outside the
camp. They disappeared.
And 3:00 in the afternoon
on April 11th, 1945,
two American soldiers walk into our
barracks.
The Messiah just arrived. There are two
of them.
I'm liberated.
No one wants to kill me anymore.
It's like suddenly
a yoke was taken away. They walk into
our barracks and there in this barracks
is a couple of hundred
skeletons shuffling along.
They can't believe their sights. They
break down.
And so
I survive.
It's a strange wonderful new feeling.
Very soon the commander, the American
commander decides that we [music] have
these couple hundred kids here, 15 year
olds, they can't we have to do something
quickly for them or else they may not
survive. And so he takes he takes us out
of the camp and puts us into a building
outside of the camp where the guards
used to live. And to each room he puts
four children, four kids like us.
And in the room are beds with mattresses
and pillows.
And we get fed three times a day.
And not only that, we get on many
occasion we get chocolate. [music]
Month goes by, transportation becomes
available. What do I do? I'm in the
middle of Germany.
outside of the city of Weimar
alone
and 15 years old. Well, one option was
to go back to Czechoslovakia because now
was reinstated again and maybe somebody
in [music] my family is alive. It's a
long track. It takes about a week or 10
days or so. And finally, I get to the
village.
First person I see I ask him [music]
anybody in the ro family survived and he
says yeah very nonchal to him he's a
Christian and nothing really happened I
say where I run over the house I open up
the door the middle of the kitchen sits
my mother
me being cool mom
looked up and she just about fainted
out of sheer joy
My father and mother survive.
I am the unusual one in that I have
parents.
When we came back to our own city, back
to Home,
you would think that the population of
Hummena would welcome.
We were not.
But the words were,
"So many Jews came back. Hitler didn't
do such a great job.
We thought we were rid of them. Hundreds
of Jews were shot in Poland after the
war. So the problem was here you have
survivors, no place to go.
So they stay in the camps.
It's not until 1947
that the world takes a major step.
November 29th,
the UN meets at a place called Lake
Success, [music] New York,
and they decide to partition Palestine
into a Palestinian state or a Arab state
and a Jewish [music] state. And after
2,000 years, the Jewish problem [music]
has been solved. The Jews have a
country.
They can go and try to form an economy
and go live in peace and harmony.
Wonderful dream.
The Jews of the world are ecstatic. But
five Arab armies attack this fledgling
state.
This state which has no air force, not
even pilots.
a rag army made up a lot of the people
who survived Awitz and other death camps
trying to stay alive.
Israel absorbed for a tiny tiny tiny
little country that was attacked and
plunged into war literally on the day of
its birth absorbed nearly a million
refugees that had been instantly
dispossessed and thrown out of Arab
countries after the Second World War.
And people saw what happened during the
Holocaust.
There was almost no anti-semitism
because nobody wanted to be associated
with the Nazis cuz they saw what
happened.
Now we're three generations later and
young people growing up
have no recollection of what happened
during World War II. They're not taught
in school. They don't see it. What they
see is what they see on the internet.
What they see is what people tell them.
And again, the age-old anti-semitism is
coming back.
We've looked and seen that almost 30% of
young people have no idea about the
Holocaust, what happened, we must
educate them. That's part of the thing
of anti-semitism.
>> I guess if there's one person out of a
billion out there who says there are no
should be no nation states in the world.
No one has a right to the state of their
own. And so therefore, the Jews don't
have a right to a [music] state of their
own. But if you say that there is this
Jewish people and we're only 4,000 years
old. I mean, I think the Chinese can
compete with us. So, you're saying all
these other countries have a right to
exist. [music] But this Jewish people
that has suffered thousands of years of
persecution.
They don't have a right to exist. They
don't have a right to have to live in
secure borders. They don't have the
right to take in Jews who are fleeing
persecution from around the world. I
think that's outrageous and I think it
has to be called out for what it is.
Anti-Zionism is anti-semitism.
>> When human life has no value, no human
life has value. [music] So we strive all
the time to to bring these messages
forward. It's not to get lost in the
Holocaust. This is not 1939. [music]
Mostly because we have an independent
and strong Jewish state and that Jewish
communities that are in danger can be
addressed. But more than that, I hope
that we have learned the lessons of the
past and that we share it. There was a
woman in the civil rights movement who
said, "We're not where we want to be.
We're not where we're going to be, but
thank God we're not where we used to
be." So, I look [music] back at the
history of persecution, pilgrim.
[music]
We're living in a free America. We have
the right to practice our faith. We're
not going to allow some people who hate
us to in any way uh remove us from our
loyalty and our love for who we are as a
people.
For years I had my views on Israel and
for years I thought I was an expert on
Israel. But I picked up this book. It
wasn't out of intellectual curiosity. It
wasn't trying to be intellectually
honest. I was so convinced that I was
right that reading this book would
reaffirm that I was right and also show
how weak the arguments of the Zionists
were. And we would say Zionist as it was
almost a Nazism. It was a negative word
when we would say it. So I start reading
this book and it challenged everything I
had ever propagated, everything I had
believed with simple rational arguments
based on evidence. Yeah. That the Jewish
people hadn't simply turned up in the
Middle East after the Holocaust. That
the Jewish people have had a presence
[music] in the Holy Land for thousands
of years. That Israel is a democracy.
That there is freedom of worship and
freedom of religion and all these
things. [music] Even with the evidence
and sources quoted, this was so far from
what I knew [music] to be the truth. It
was absurd to me. This obsessive search
goes on for almost two years, but I
still wasn't willing to believe that I
was wrong. I couldn't I mean, think
about it. I spent years, invested
[music] years of emotion, essentially
hatred into how I feel. I can't now go
with the idea which I am ready mentally
and and
spiritually, I guess, to kill people, to
kill Jews because I know what I'm doing
is right. can't now go well I [music]
was wrong. I I couldn't make that jump
and I was having these kind of you could
say depression essentially because it's
very difficult to go from this is my
truth and I believe and I've invested
years of my life into it but nothing is
validating that and not seeing a way out
of this kind of loop I decided that I
had to go to Israel and see it for self.
And again, it wasn't this journey of I
want to actually go find out the truth.
It was I want to prove that I'm right
and if I go to Israel, I'll get treated
awfully. I have a Muslim name, I'm
Muslim, you know, my I have Pakistani
roots. It will be this awful experience
and I will see it firsthand and I can
then continue the plan I have for my
life. So I arrive in Israel at Bengorian
airport and I get to the passport
control counter and hand over my
passport and they say, "What is the
purpose of your visit?" So I was very
honest. Yeah, I was that naive. I was
like, well, look, I used to be
anti-semitic and anti-Israel, and now
I'm not really sure. So, I thought I'd
come and see it for myself. And that's
how I ended up spending 8 hours in
Israeli security. Majorly my own fault.
And I can accept that. And as as crazy
as it may sound, that was the starting
point of everything now that I think
about it and over the years I have
thought about it because [music] what 8
hours is a long time. The officer that
questioned me,
it humanized Israelis. [music] It
humanized someone Jewish for the first
time. He's respectful and he's
apologetic. He does something which I am
dubbed now kind of the the alternative
to the good cup bad cup. He does like
the good cup Jewish mother thing where
he keeps trying to continually feed me
meals. Um, and even when I say I'm good,
I still end up with coffee and meals.
But eventually I leave the airport and I
go to Jerusalem which was my first stop
and I do all the mundane things that you
do checking into your hotel etc. But
then when I actually went out into
Jerusalem and I had this real mindset of
this is an apartheid state. I'm going to
see segregation. I'm going to see
Jewishonly buses. I'm going to see
Arabon [music] only stores. And
straight away that was completely
torpedoed. You walk for less than 2
minutes in Jerusalem and you'll see
Arab-Israelis, Jewish Israelis,
ultraorththodox women with headscarves,
Greek Orthodox priests, all going about
life.
And I made an effort to speak to [music]
people. I spoke to Israeli Jews, both
religious and secular, Jews who'd come
from Ethiopia and China. I spoke to
Arab-Israelis, Christian and Muslims.
But it was still so difficult to process
because I'm at this point where now I'm
seeing it. I'm not reading it. I'm
seeing it firsthand. I'm hearing it from
the people who are living it. But I
still [music] can't make that that jump
from this was the truth. I'm wrong.
There was this moment where I was like,
"Now what?" So I was in Israel for a few
more weeks and I went to the Palestinian
territories too and I spoke to people. I
went to Yadvashm for example, um the
Holocaust Memorial Center and and the
logical step for me was to learn more.
>> [music]
[music]
>> What is the point? Why why is this
obsession with almost divorcing the
Jewish people from the land of Israel
and Jerusalem specifically? I I think
that if you take the opposition to
Israel today, whether it's coming from
certain segments of Palestinian society,
whether it's coming from bodies in the
United Nations like UNESCO and other
forces in Europe, there is an opposition
to the idea of the return of the Jewish
people to Israel. The idea of having a
sovereign Jewish state in this part of
the world bothers people. It bothers
them politically. It bothers some people
theologically. And what's the problem?
If in the archaeological excavations
that are taking place throughout this
country, but here specifically in the
city of David, if we're able to unearth
antiquities [music] that show not simply
as a matter of faith, but as a matter of
fact, the connection of Jews to
Jerusalem, to the land of Israel, well,
that's very inconvenient because the
story that's being told is that we're a
bunch of colonizers. We're a bunch of
occupiers. We're thieves. And it's like,
well, wait a minute. When we pull a seal
out of the ground [music] with the name
of figures from the Bible, when we
unearth inscription here that affirm
events that took place in the Bible,
when we affirm massive thorough affairs
that match up with the description of
Jerusalem and people making pilgrimage
up to the temple, well, that's
inconvenient because it's showing that
you may have your political beliefs, you
may have your ideological beliefs, you
may have your theological beliefs, but
this is real. We have been here. It's
not a subject for debate.
[music]
This is where the Jewish people, this is
where Christianity was getting its start
in Jerusalem during the first century of
the common era. This is the biblical
superighway from 2,000 years ago. Again,
not simply as a matter of faith because
it says so in the Bible, but because
it's a matter of fact. This is what the
archaeology is showing us in this place.
This is one of the greatest physical
affirmations when you could touch it,
right? This is the actual road. It's the
actual history. This is not stones that
were put here uh or well, they look
really good here. This is how the
archaeologists found it. This is the
actual road in the actual place with the
actual flag stones that our ancestors
walked on thousands of years ago.
[music]
We we've been looking at the increase in
anti-semitism today um in Europe,
[music] in North America, and given your
academic experience and other
experiences, if you could put a
solution, not a solution, but ideas or
ways forward Ward. Is it education? Is
it changing a narrative?
What do you think is the way we can
impact this?
The media the media has a tremendous
potential. I think that um
from an earlier earliest age
children could be educated towards
tolerance of and respect of the other
and the positive
effect
of such
a relationship.
And I do think that two very powerful
elements
are education, mass education,
not indoctrination
and the use of the media.
>> Yeah.
>> So the mood of media and educational
policies are determined by politics and
politicians.
>> [laughter]
>> So again, you're back to the same
problem when the politicians have their
own agenda and their own prejudices and
their own religious positions.
reading the case for Israel was the
first time and yeah this may sound for
somebody who was born in Britain for me
to say this even looking back seems a
little strange. It was the first time I
had actually looked at a Jewish person
as almost human.
>> I I I know. And for me, it's just
confronting this as I'm thinking this
out because anything written by somebody
Jewish was instantly dismissed by me as
these people have evil intentions. And
that was the first time. Yeah. and and I
I didn't approach it from page one with
this h but the more I read it there was
this humanizing factor to it and it
addressed things in a human and very
real way and one thing that to this day
sticks out to me uh cuz I was rereading
it it recently again when you talk about
one of your professors when you were
studying who said Jews cheat and you
everybody cheats It's well
and that's something I'd done my whole
life. These things that everybody does,
but the Jews do it
>> and it's so easy to do that.
>> Uh you can't generalize about people. I
was lucky cuz I taught at a university
for 50 years and I've had Palestinian
students, wonderful students, brilliant
students, humanistic students. You know,
I would share a seder meal with them and
then we'd share a Ramadan meal together.
So, you know, when the biggest cure for
anti-semitism are Jews and the biggest
cure for anti-Islam feeling are meeting
a range of Muslims. I have friends who
say when there's a letter to the editor
of the New York Times, they just look at
the name, they don't even read it. And
if it is an Arab name, they're going to
dismiss it. Yeah. And I'm sure on the
other side, people who say, "Oh, if
there's a witz at the end of the name or
a berg at the end of the name, we know
what they're going to say." So, you
dismiss it. purposely tried to write my
book in a way that was a little
counterintuitive that made it clear that
the Palestinian there are there are
perspectives from the Palestinian side
that really deserve to be considered and
that um much of the blame lies with the
leadership of the Palestinian movement
rather than with everyday Palestinians,
Muslims or Arabs. I hope the book
succeeded in at least not discounting
the emotional arguments on both sides.
>> Well, as you hear, I [music] I didn't
grow up in this country. I have an
American accent because I grew up in the
United States in a small town in
northern New Jersey. Grew up in a
workingclass neighborhood where I was
the only [music] uh Jewish kid. I was
exposed to a lot of anti-semitism pretty
much daily. Used to get beat up and when
I [music] come home from school all sort
of bloody. My father would take me down
to the basement and open up an old
photograph album that he had kept from
World War II. He and his brother had
landed on Normandy Beach, had fought
across Europe. And in the course of
their uh war, they they liberated a
concentration camp. And he had pictures
of this concentration camp and piles of
scorched bodies, skeletons, laughing
Nazis. and he would point at these
pictures and he'd say, "You see that?
You see that, son? That's why we need a
strong state of Israel." And that had a
profound impact on me and on my decision
to move here.
>> I frequently hear, be it on campuses or
on social media, is that BDS isn't
anti-Semitic.
That it's about Israel. It's not about
the Jews.
How accurate is that?
>> But of course, it's anti-Semitic.
Anti-semitism by definition, even by the
definition of the United Nations, even
by the definition of the European Union,
is singling [music]
Jews out for special treatment, for
special censure. The BDS is not a is not
an organization that stcri aspires to
create peace, to create a better
two-state solution. It talks about
destroying the world's only sovereign
Jewish state and denying [music]
the Jewish people's right to
self-determination in their homeland.
that by any definition, UN, [music]
European, otherwise is anti-Semitic.
[music]
Syria is a country with no peace
agreements with Israel. And when you
look at Syrian propaganda, it's not just
anti-Israel, it's anti-Semitic, [music]
very obviously. So what makes Israel go
one, okay, we're going to reinforce our
positions, but we actually want to
actively [music]
help these people? Cuz it's very easy to
defend your borders and look the other
way. How do you make that choice? And
why did you [music] make that choice
that we need to actively help these
people some of them who have grown up
maybe the majority with pure hatred for
who we are and our core identity from
your perspective?
>> I will answer about this question uh
without speaking with your permission.
>> Okay, for sure.
If you can just take a look at that
picture,
I think that everybody that will see it
[music] can understand why we did it.
>> Yeah.
>> Because this is a part of operation. We
called it doctor's visit. The meaning of
doctor's visit operation was to take
care for 25 children, not wounded
children.
>> They were suffering from chronical
diseases.
>> And we decided [music] that once a week
we would take them to the Israeli
hospitals. They will meet some expert
Israeli doctors,
treat them and then they will go back to
Syria. Now [music] when you met those
children and I have three of my own, you
cannot uh live it without the solution
without trying to help. Yes, the mission
was to take him to the hospital but we
did other things. I I never thought that
I will play with Syrian children when I
wearing my uniform. But when we saw that
smile on that children child boy face or
this girl face, we're [music]
understanding that we're just doing the
right thing to do as human beings.
>> It's really I mean it's [music] it's
very special to think of these Syrian
children growing up with what their
parents thought and yeah, they've come
from a war zone and they're smiling.
It's just it's really impactful and I
didn't I didn't expect that to happen
either. Um what is common for [music]
all of these testimonies is the word
hope. They continue survived because
they got hope [music] and what happened
in that project that I think that we was
the only country in the world [music]
that provided hope for those people. We
gave them the power to to live in this
six very bad years of them. [music]
And I'm almost sure
what I think that it left inside Syria
is 250,000 people [music]
that know who is the state of Israel. It
will be very hard to convince them
[music] that we are the devil again. And
I think that maybe some of them will be
in the future our enemies again.
I think that most of them will think
twice
if someone will offer them to go against
the state of Israel because deep in
their heart they know that we chose to
risk our lives.
So I took some time to be a tourist
while I was there because it was very
heavy and it was very kind of difficult
to process all of this and I go to the
old city in Jerusalem and I go to the
temple mount the Alexa mosque. I go to
the church of the holy sepula and I go
to the western wall which is the last
remaining wall from the temple. So I go
I go to the security checkpoint and I go
through no issues. I'm like, "Okay." I'm
walking towards the Western Wall. I'm
trying to process like, "What what do I
do here? How do how is this going to
work
and I get there and I copy the guy next
to me who [music] has his hand on the
wall and put my hand on the wall and
eventually my forehead's against the
[music] western wall." And it really was
a I don't want to make it too much of a
cliche and call it a spiritual
experience, but it really was. There was
this moment of clarity.
As noisy as life can be, as noisy as
both internal and external noises can
be, I had a real moment to process
everything I'd experienced in the last
few days. And I mean the years preceding
that because I thought here I am in
Israel.
I'm in a Jewish state. I mean Jerusalem.
I've met Israelis and Jewish people for
the first time and actually had
conversations.
I've met people from different
backgrounds.
And these are people that I hated. These
are people that when buses were being
blown up in 2000 and 2001 in Jerusalem
and Tel Aviv, I felt like they deserved
it. There wasn't this this is awful. A
bus with women and children has been
blown up. I felt they genuinely deserved
it. When 9/11 happened, rather than
being horrified, there was this element
of, well, I think America really
deserved it. They brought this on
themselves.
And that was scary in that moment cuz I
thought, how have you gotten to this
point?
But you've gotten to the point where
thousands of people getting murdered
going to work, women and children
getting murdered just going to the store
is okay with you based on nothing. These
people have never done anything to you.
You've never met anybody Jewish. Nobody
Jewish or Israeli has anybody done
anything to harm you or your family.
What has happened? How did this happen?
I genuinely thought I was doing the
right thing. But that realization that
your moral compass is not broken but
[music] completely non-existent is it's
difficult.
But rather than dwell on that and just
be, you know, feeling self-pity, I
looked at the situation in that moment.
I'm in Jerusalem. I'm in Israel. And
something that really resonated with me,
there were two things. One, it was the
moment I could go, I'm wrong. I've got
this completely wrong.
And there is 6 million Jews who will
never see this. They will never see the
rebirth of the Jewish state.
Jews who pray next year in Jerusalem,
6 million will never see Jerusalem. They
will never see the rebirth of the state
that could have made all the difference.
But I do believe that if there was an
Israel in 1935,
6 million Jews would not have been
murdered in Europe because they would
have [music] had a homeland. they would
have had somewhere to go because history
is a brutal reminder that when Jews were
escaping Germany and tried to come to
Canada or Britain or the United States,
we sent them back. We sent them back to
[music] the gas chambers.
We say this this phrase never again and
it is powerful. Never again means so
much. But sadly, when it really comes
down to it, you look at Darl, you look
at Bosnia, you look at Rwanda, never
again has not meant that much.
Unfortunately, it's not been enough to
make people act. But for the Jewish
people, there is a guarantee of never
again. And that guarantee is the [music]
state of Israel.
Never again will they have to look to
others to protect them, to defend them.
Never again will the Jewish people have
to look to an uncaring world to save
them while their children are being
murdered. And that was incredibly
powerful for me, that realization. I got
to this point when I was getting ready
to leave. I had made a few decisions. I
I knew that I was wrong. I knew that I
had gotten this really wrong and I had
to now make a choice of where to go from
this. And I had essentially two choices.
I could go, okay, I got this wrong. Life
goes on. I'm just going to step away
altogether. [music]
Or I talk about this.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Oo,
[music]
you Ooh,
>> [music]
>> We live in a in an awful time where
anti-semitism is rising again.
>> [music]
>> I mean, it's it's mindboggling that
after everything has that has happened,
after all the horror we've seen
inflicted on the Jewish community, they
are once again the target. I ended up
leaving the UK because it's very
difficult, especially when you come from
a very tight-knit community and and
those places that you grew [music] up,
those places that you'd go are no longer
open to you. You're seen almost as an
enemy. And I have very limited contact
with my family. Occasionally I'll get,
you know, death threats via social media
from people who refuse to use spellch
check. And I will speak at college
campuses and deal with incredible
hostility and people screaming at me
before I've even spoken. But do I regret
the choices I've made? No. Because
ultimately, and as cliche as it sounds,
because it's the right thing to do. Most
terrifying thing for me is [music] not
the rising level of brazen
anti-semitism. What terrifies me is the
level of apathy among ordinary people.
Good people who care about their
communities, who care about causes that
[music] don't directly relate to them,
who want the world to be a better place.
There is such great apathy when it comes
to the Jewish people. There's such great
apathy [music]
when it comes to Jews being attacked.
And I don't understand why. I don't want
to I'm not going to brand everybody as
an anti-semite. And I also think people
just don't know. And that's something I
can't remain silent about. I have to
speak out because
it's wrong. And for me, whether you
believe in God or not, whatever you
believe, you are accountable for what
you do. At some point, I genuinely
believe you're going to be accountable
for what you do. And I do not want to
look back and ever think that I could
have done more.
I I I think one of the challenges we
have in the United States across a range
of issues that includes [music]
attitudes towards Israel and includes
attitudes towards anti-semitism and
[music] the Jewish community and and
again as I said a whole range of others
is that many Americans are living in
self-contained echo chambers. Um and
they watch certain television stations
and not others. They read certain
newspapers and not others. We've lost a
common table or town square, [music] so
to speak, where you'll hear different
points of view and you'll be challenged
to give a second thought to an idea that
you heard um and and [music] to really
think critically about it and get
yourself educated about it.
>> What BDS is is a moral assault against
Israel. It's a moral attack. It's
[music] an attempt to turn Israel into a
pariah among the nations. And it starts
with words and it ends up with attacks.
[music] And we have to fight it in moral
terms. We have to confront the leaders
of BDS.
>> Of all the nations in the world uh that
are rogue in many ways [music] that are
that are dehumanize its citizens, Israel
is the target of this movement. What
other country in the world is the
[music] target of a movement similar to
BDS?
None. And so long as we think that it
somehow [music] can be isolated from the
rest of us, that it's okay to take the
Jew [music] and put the Jew at the back
of the bus or the Jewish state at the
back of the bus and the rest of us will
still be better off, that we will be
[music] able to uh somehow carry on that
human rights, even though human rights
enables anti-semitism,
can still be a success, we won't [music]
make a difference. We can't build a
human rights system on the inequality of
the Jew or the Jewish state. [music] And
that's what we've done.
>> Anti-semitism,
bad for Jews, bad for everyone. It's not
just a an issue that relates to Jews,
but relates to all of us and relates to
the health of our civil society, our
social cohesion, our civic discourse.
Young people need to
experience
understand [music]
the power that these acts of hatred,
the impact that it has. There's only one
way to fight that and that's through
education. And I don't only mean
education and anti-semitism. Yes, we
have to do that. We have to educate on
the Holocaust and we have to educate on
the evils of anti-semitism. But
ultimately we also have to educate in
phosmitism. We've got to teach every kid
in every classroom in every city in the
world what the contributions are that
the Jewish people have made to each
country and to civilization at large.
So in 2014 I had left England for Canada
and began settling into my new [music]
life. But I still wanted to speak out
and share my story. As a result, I ended
up connecting with Christians United for
Israel and was given the opportunity to
speak [music] at campuses and churches
and conferences all over the United
States.
What I saw there, the genuine support
and love for Israel exhibited [music] by
Kufi, it had a profound impact on me.
Welcome to the Holocaust Center.
And from that day to this, I've been
fighting this battle side by side with
some of the most dedicated [music]
individuals I've ever met.
So, my first interaction with Irving was
many years ago when we did a a speaking
tour together in California. We talked
and we had a week together. And I mean,
Irving is incredible. just his stories,
his humor, and his real
love for life, you know, just everything
he's experienced. And you speak to
Irving, and on one hand, he's telling
you about this experience at Awitz and
[music] then he can then be telling you
the funniest story from two weeks ago.
And it's it's this strange paradox, but
just meeting Irving has such an impact
on me on on multiple ways because here
is a guy who's experienced horrors that
you not most of us cannot even be
imagine. I can't imagine what Irving
went through. I can't you know [music]
you watch Schindler's List, you've
watched the documentaries, you read the
books, but this was his life. This is
what he experienced.
Yet here he is and he's living life to
its fullest. and he's funny and all
these things and and sharing what he
experienced, but he's not being a victim
to what he experienced. And that was it
was inspiring,
but it was al almost a wakeup call. It
was for me a reminder of speaking up was
bigger than me. It was bigger than I had
really seen it. And then you meet Irving
and you're like, really, dude? Like
you're feeling sorry for yourself. Like
come on. And that was energizing for me.
And that really made me rethink [music]
where I was at and where I was feeling
and re dedicate myself more to it
because [music] it became very real at
that point.
I want to thank you for having me in
your wonderful home. It means a lot. And
uh like we said at when we were at the
museum, what you do, the work you do
[music] has been such a inspiration to
me personally and I want to thank you
for that.
>> Well, it's a both a pleasure and a
privilege to have you because we had an
opportunity to speak about many of the
details. I'll look at [music] some of
the photographs, the images
and of course for you to know that and
your commitment to tell the story
becomes an extremely important piece of
what I try to do [music] that you must
do. Essentially, I would say I hope and
trust [music] you will be a surrogate
survivor. The fact that we have you
working with other people today within
Kufi,
seven and a half million Christians in
America [music] saying not on our watch,
never again out there beating the bushes
day in and day out telling the students
fighting a current, an evil current.
And with God's help, you will achieve
that. what you survived and what you've
done since then. You you refuse to be a
victim.
And [music] if we're gonna credit how
we've grown and how Kufi has grown and
the work we're doing, you're front and
center of that. Just being around you
has refocused me in the importance of
this. [music] And I can't I can't
predict the future. I can't predict what
will happen. But I do promise you that
one, the Jewish people aren't alone.
You're not alone. Your children, your
grandchildren aren't alone. We, you
know, we will fight shoulderto-shoulder
with you against anti-semitism. When we
say when I say never again, I mean never
again. I I want to dedicate my actions
and what I do to making sure that's a
reality and not just a statement.
>> There are issues we need to fight, but
that we are not alone.
This is absorbed,
understood [music] and felt.
My heart is full
and it truly been a privilege
for that.
>> Thank you.
>> I thank you guys. You've been much loved
and remembered forever.
We talked about the Holocaust and we
know it's a an awful thing, but here is
your face to face with someone who went
through it and it became so real to me.
I've heard the phrase, you know, you
don't have skin in the game. And that's
why I got the tattoo that I'm not
walking away that we're in this with
you, Irving, till the end. There is no
walking away. this isn't a something
we're going to do for 5 years and then
when it gets tough we're going to walk
away because for Irving for people who
are Jewish they don't get to walk away
and I don't want to walk away either and
I refuse to
People
have to [music] change and the change is
very simple. Instead of focusing on the
past, people have to focus on the
future.
>> But the whole idea of never again was a
Jew should never find [music] themselves
in a position where they're dependent
upon someone else's power.
uh essentially is what um has come to be
termed how does [music] how do Jews
become the subject of their own
sentences not the object of someone
else's and how do they pres preserve and
protect the right of self-determination
[music]
>> we have to start being aware of the
power of our words the words that are
spoken and also the words that aren't
spoken right when [music] we don't stand
up when we don't speak out against hate
um and realize that even if we don't
[music] intend it to go a certain way
once we set it out there we have no way
of controlling [music] the narrative and
therefore we have to be so careful, so
weary of what we're saying um and making
sure that we're spreading love and not
hate.
>> My hope is not only for to stop
anti-semitism,
to stop Islamophobia, to stop Christian
hate. We must have a country and world
that lives [music] in love and not hate.
That's my hope for the future.
>> The options are are are really two. You
can look at the situation and say ah
it's hopeless [music] and nothing to be
done and move on or just whail and or
you can dedicate yourself to looking at
what might be possible [music] and try
to not be a person who helped to let a
good opportunity pass by. And I would
much [music] prefer the second. It
doesn't take more effort particularly.
It just takes a different attitude.
>> Those people who want to help Jews
should not just focus on mourning Jews
who were murdered decades ago. They
should stand with the Jews in
confronting those who would murder the
Jews today. That is [music] ultimately
the test of words like never again or
we'll never forget. To make it real, you
have to stand with the Jews when they're
alive. And you have a live Jewish state,
9 million citizens in our country
fighting against forces who seek the
destruction of our country. And you
[music] see w a wave of anti-semitism
that's engulfing uh different parts of
the world. governments should push back
against it. They should push back
against hatred of Jews and also this new
anti-semitism.
>> So, we've seen anti-semitism [music]
raise its ugly head in Europe, in the
Middle East, and even in North America.
And we have to fight it.
We can't allow anti-semitism to
masquerade under masks that, you know,
we're only against Israel or we're only
against something else. I believe if you
if you expose the anti-semmites for what
they are, which is uh propagators of
hatred, I think that's probably the best
way to fight them.
>> Americans need to stand together and
stand against this hatred in a united
front to say never again. We won't
tolerate the demonization of the Jewish
people. We won't tolerate the
demonization of the Jewish state. And if
all good, decent people who who care
about justice and who love decency stand
together, we're going to win this fight.
All the stories that people make up
throughout the world
about the Jew, my brother,
gentle,
kind,
sweet human,
though he's been murdered
because of who he was, a Jew.
And though his body no longer exists,
it hasn't for decades.
But in me, his soul
is alive today here
and telling us all,
"Love your neighbor."
that the stranger among you have the
same rights
as you any other fellow human being.
It is that message from him to me to
you.
When you see evil, when you hear evil,
do not close your eyes.
Do not stuff your ears.
Be there.
We are here for a limited time on this
earth. We would all come here the same
way. [snorts]
No one leaves this earth alive.
How will you and I be judged?
Will our grandchildren be able to say
my grandfather was a murderer?
Or will he be able to say
to this human?
I've learned from him
and must carry his spirit,
his soul, his goodness.
The world is given to us to manage.
We can do it.
My name is Kasim Hafi. I was raised a
radical Muslim and was taught to hate
Jews in Israel from a young age. I
decided that terrorism, murdering
civilians who did not see the world as I
did in order to advance my agenda, was
my calling. But then I learned the
truth. I came to know that what I had
been taught about Jews was wrong.
I saw for myself that the media reports
and international condemnations of the
Jewish state were lies. Israel is a free
and democratic state. Its citizens are
recorded full human and civil rights. As
this body recently displayed by brazenly
lying about Israel's actions in Gaza,
hatred towards the Jewish state
persists. But make no mistake, those who
foster anti-semitism at the UN, at this
council, who build their careers and
foreign policy on a foundation of Jew
hatred will be judged harshly by
history. When you demonize the Jewish
state, it is a reflection of your moral
bankruptcy and nothing more. I know this
because I was just as wrong.
At my university, anti-semitic
propaganda is on the rise.
>> Anti-semitism is miseducation and
misinformation.
>> Anti-semitism is evil. Anti-semitism is
blatant racism [music] against the
Jewish people.
>> Anti-semitism is an unfortunate disease
that should be eradicated. Anti-semitism
is
judgmental.
>> Anti-semitism is an issue that I will
fight back [music] against.
Anti-semitism is demonizing the Jewish
people.
>> Anti-semitism
is not the love that me or anybody else
deserves.
>> Anti-semitism
is darkness.
is leaving me speechless.
The cries of the broken
world of emotions.
A vision is focused.
The secrets rees
come
true.
And [music]
the sound of color
to teach us
[music]
again. [music]
>> [music]
>> The past is real
on the backs of our fathers.
The legacy is clear.
The word you spoken
make the curses [music]
broken.
So the generation found it
and finding [music]
[music]
the sun.
>> [music]
>> Never again.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Heat. Heat. [music]
[music]
The Holocaust began with words
uttered by individuals,
repeated by others,
and became a philosophy, an ideology.
And when you hear those words,
wherever it comes from,
you must do something about it. This we
must not allow to happen again.
[music]
Heat. Heat.